I finally found her.
終於找到了
What did she do at that summer festival? No, what will she do?
這孩子在夏日慶典上做了甚麼 不，是打算做甚麼
If I can find that out, I can stop her!
只要弄清楚這一點就能阻止她
Hiruko appears in the form of Heine, whom she copied first.
這是蛭子大人最初所複製的 波稻的模樣
She enjoys being called by that name.
她喜歡別人用這個名字稱呼她
She is the god of Hitogashima Island. Hiruko-no-Mikoto, mother of the shadows.
她正是日都島的神，蛭子命 影子們的母親
This kid… is a god?
你說這孩子是神？
Recently, due to poor nutrition, her legs have weakened.
最近因為身體營養失調 雙腳發軟，走不動了
She needed another body.
需要一個可以替代的身體
How many times have we met like this?
像這樣和你見面是第幾次了？
Shinpei Ajiro.
網代慎平
You were still alive.
你還活著嗎？
You did it.
就是你做的嗎？
You killed Ushio. You killed Mio.
殺害潮，殺害澪
You're the monster who swallowed up the island.
吞噬這座島的怪物
You were the god of this island?
就是這座島的神？
You were right there from the beginning…
這傢伙一直…從一開始就一直…
in front of me all along!
一直就在我眼前嗎？
Shinpei, step back!
慎平，快後退
No, Heine!
不行，波稻
NIGHT OF BLOOD
（第12集　血夜）
His loud voice echoes in my head and irritates me.
可是這傢伙的大嗓門 在我腦子裡嗡嗡作響，令我很煩躁
I almost killed you by accident.
我會一不小心就會殺掉他
I like my meals in silence. Don't speak to me again.
我喜歡安靜地吃飯，別再跟我說話了
Tokiko.
朱鷺子
Ms. Negoro?
根來小姐？
She's a nurse at our clinic.
是我們醫院的護士
An average of four die each year on Hitogashima Island…
日都島每年平均的死亡人數是四人
by illness or accident.
因為生病或是遭遇意外
You figured it out.
你已經明白了吧
We have always given those dead people to her.
我們菱形醫院一直以來 都把那些死人提供給她
My father too.
爸爸…
My grandfather, great-grandfather, and so on.
祖父、曾祖父，還有以前的先人們 都是這麼做
What's with the coffins? Don't tell me you feed people to her!
那些棺材是怎麼回事？ 該不會是讓那孩子吃人吧
I was waiting for this. Quite a feast today.
我等好久了，今天也很豐盛啊
Tomorrow shall be even bigger.
明天會更豐盛
I said you weren't capable of killing.
我之前說過慎平哥殺不了人吧
But I am prepared to die by your hands.
但我已經做好了 被慎平哥殺掉的心理準備
Wait. Tokiko, it can't be…
等一下，朱鷺子，難道…
Come closer and take a look, Ushioh.
靠近點仔細看看，潮
This is your original that I missed out on eating.
這是那時候 我沒來得及吃下的你的原型
No! Ushio!
怎麼會這樣？潮
Is it Ushio?
這真的是潮？那昨天火化的遺體呢？ 我們撿的遺骨呢？
Father switched out her body. Heine printed those bones from someone.
遺體被爸爸換包了 骨頭是波稻列印出來的別人的骨頭
Why? Why go that far? Why take care of her?
為甚麼為了照料這孩子 不惜做到這種程度？
Tokiko, you knew everything? Shiori being targeted?
朱鷺子，你全都知道嗎？ 包括詩織被盯上
Ushio being killed?
還有潮被殺害的事
I didn't know about Ushio.
我不知道潮姐姐的事
I had no idea she and her shadow were working together to save Shiori.
沒想到她會和自己的影子聯手 去救詩織
She died because she got involved in something that she shouldn't have.
她是因為自以為正義 多管閒事才會死的
What?
你說甚麼？
This was all for Heine.
這一切都是為了波稻
Shut up! I can't forgive this!
開甚麼玩笑？ 你怎麼能做這種喪盡天良的事？
Where is the old man?
爸爸在哪裡？
You don't know anything! Shut your mouth, idiot!
你甚麼都不知道 就別大吵大鬧了，混蛋
It's all because of you that I got stuck with this!
就因為哥哥你這樣 這些事才會由我來做啊
I didn't have a choice. I didn't.
我只能這麼做，只能這樣
If Heine dies, so would Mother.
要是波稻死了，媽媽也會死
What?
甚麼？
Mother is alive not because her sickness is gone.
媽媽現在能活著，不是因為病治好了
Father begged Heine to turn her into a shadow to keep her alive.
是因為爸爸拜託了波稻 把她變成影子，所以才沒有死
What? What do you mean?
甚麼？不…甚麼意思？
I don't get this. Mother is… What?
我聽不懂你在說甚麼 媽媽她…甚麼？
Both you and Shinpei…
哥哥和慎平哥不也是…
treat Ushioh like the real Ushio, don't you?
把影子潮當成真正的潮姐姐了嗎？
Tokiko.
朱鷺子…
No.
不行
I can't let Ushio be eaten by her and disappear!
我絕對不能讓潮被那傢伙吃掉 從此消失
Shadows freeze for a few seconds during a scan. It's the same for Heine.
影子在掃描時，有幾秒鐘不能動彈 波稻也不例外
Now, Ushioh! Print!
潮，趁現在，快列印
I was waiting for you to say that!
就等你這句話了
Take this!
去死吧
Ushioh!
潮
Are you hurt?
沒受傷吧？
No fair! You stole my dinner!
太狡猾了，搶走了我的食物
Thanks, Ushioh. Are you okay?
謝謝你，潮，你沒事吧？
The right time's upon us. Now I…
是時候了，快把我…
Why?
為甚麼？
Why fight against shadows? Are you stupid?
竟然要反抗影子，你是笨蛋嗎？
You'll just die. You can't win. There's no way.
只有死路一條，贏不了的
The Tokiko I know won't do this willingly.
我所認識的朱鷺子 不是一個會心甘情願做這種事的人
It's just using you…
那傢伙只是在利用你
taking advantage of your weakness.
抓住你們的弱點
It's playing with your emotions to feed its hunger.
為了填飽自己的肚子 玩弄朱鷺子的感情
Can you just accept that? Because I never would!
怎麼能接受這樣的壓迫活下去？ 絕對不行
Don't be messing with my sister's best friend.
竟敢蔑視我妹妹重要的好朋友
A god, Hiruko, whatever you are. Don't underestimate humans!
我才不管你是神還是蛭子大人
Ushioh.
潮姐姐…
Boring.
真沒意思
What?
那是甚麼？
No more need to copy humans?
已經沒必要擬態成人類了嗎？
I want to eat Ushio's memories.
我想吃潮的記憶
Leave him for dead.
打到半死就行了
The best option now…
最好的對策是…
is for Ushioh to break my neck and for me to loop back.
讓潮砍下我的腦袋，馬上進入輪迴
That was actually my plan.
實際上之前也是這麼打算的
I need to avoid exposing Ushioh to any more danger.
必須避免讓潮陷入危險的戰鬥中
But…
但是…
I should stop Ushioh, but I can't.
我應該阻止潮的，卻沒有阻止
I know why.
因為…
Both Ushioh and I…
我和潮…
There it is!
來了
…share the same feeling!
擁有完全相同的感受
Don't underestimate humans!
別小看人類！
If I'm dying anyway, I'll fight and die.
反正都要死，不如戰鬥至死
Shin…
慎…
Stop, Heine. That's enough.
行了，波稻，到此為止吧
You just tried to eat Shinpei, didn't you?
你剛才想吃掉慎平吧？
But they took my food!
因為這些人把我的食物都…
It doesn't matter.
別找藉口
Don't worry, Heine.
沒事，波稻
I'll get Ushio Kofune's body back.
小舟潮的遺體，我稍後會搶回來的
You can't eat this one. She's an important hostage.
但這個不能吃，這可是重要的人質
-Mio!
-澪
Shut up. I know already.
真煩人，我知道了
Don't worry. Mio is alive.
別擔心，小澪還活著
However, if you make even one step,
但是如果你們敢移動一步
I'll crush her head like an egg.
我就把她的腦袋像捏生雞蛋一樣捏碎
Hey. What is this?
喂，這是甚麼意思？
You said you wouldn't touch Mio!
不是說好了不會對澪下手嗎？
Don't get so upset. Everyone will die tomorrow, anyway.
沒甚麼意思，反正明天大家都會死
What are you saying?
你在說甚麼？
The last meal at the summer festival tomorrow…
明天的夏日慶典進行最後的進食 讓波稻的身體康復
and Mother will live again.
媽媽就可以繼續活下去
Everything will be back to normal, just how Father planned it, right?
之後一切如常，這是爸爸的計劃
We appreciate the Hishigatas' support. However, that shall end soon.
我們一直以來承蒙菱形家的關照 但這也已經結束了
You betrayed us.
你們背叛了我們
-What will you do to us? -Tokiko!
你們要對大家做甚麼？
Whoa!
天啊
Brother…
哥哥
Your father is aware of all of this.
你父親對這一切都很清楚
No. I can't stay conscious.
不行了，我的意識已經…
Sis…
姐姐…
Hey, are you okay? You're all bloody!
喂，你沒事吧？你流了好多血
Totsumura. Thank goodness. He's human.
凸村？太好了，他是人類
I'm done for.
我只能到這裡了
I'm sorry, Sis.
抱歉了，姐姐
Ryunosuke.
龍之介…
You were at Ushio's funeral, the lady with the H-cup boobs.
你是小潮葬禮上那個H罩杯
They're G, dummy!
是G，混蛋
She was with you.
你們應該是一起進來的吧
A-A monster took her.
被怪物帶走了
Where's your gun?
你的手槍呢？
I dropped it somewhere. I took it out and shot at them.
應該是掉了，我拔出槍想開槍打他們
I fell, then I ran. I don't remember anything after that.
結果摔倒了，然後我就跑 之後的事我都不記得了
Running was the right choice.
逃跑是正確的
What?
甚麼？
I need your help.
我有事要你幫忙
I can't walk anymore. So I need you to carry me.
我已經走不動了 所以請你把我送過去
No, take me to the deepest part of this cave.
不，送我到這個洞窟的最深處
No.
不行
I can't let this be real.
不能讓這一切變成現實
Ushioh.
潮
Come here. Slowly.
過來這裡，慢慢地
I won't forgive you!
你們這些傢伙，不可原諒
Who cares if you won't? Do you want Mio to die?
不可原諒又如何？小澪會死的
Come.
過來
Stop.
住手
Don't touch her. If you want to eat humans, eat me!
別動她，你不是想吃人嗎？ 那就吃了我
No point in dying in style.
想要慷慨赴死嗎？沒用的
I was wrong to call you a dud.
之前說你是劣化的野生種，我更正
You couldn't defeat Negoro if you were.
那樣的傢伙怎麼可能打倒根來？
You're not broken. In fact, you've evolved.
你不但沒有劣化，反而在成長
It's a waste to erase you.
就這樣消除你就太可惜了
Instead, I'll fix your head and use you.
我要把你的腦子修好再利用
I need labor for tomorrow.
畢竟明天需要人手
No! Shinpei!
不要，慎平
Please stop!
給我住手
What? I guess I can't erase his power.
甚麼？無法消除這傢伙的力量嗎？
Which came first, the chicken or the egg?
是先有蛋還是先有雞 因果形成迴圈了
Not fair!
真狡猾
Your right eye can step back and see the flow of time from a higher dimension.
你的右眼可以從高維空間的視角 俯瞰時間的流逝
It observes multiple parallel worlds.
觀測多個平行世界
So, Shinpei.
而慎平你…
You can make the world you observe into reality.
你擁有將你觀測到的世界 變為現實的力量
You are rendering this world.
現在這個世界由是你在彩現 真是可怕的神之力
However, you are not skilled in using that power.
但你還沒能熟練掌握這股力量
You can't activate it unless you lose self-awareness by dying.
如果沒有死這種自我意識的消失 就不會發動，是不完全的狀態
In other words, we just need to not kill you.
總而言之 只要把你的生命留到最後一刻就行了
How simple.
很簡單
Just keep breathing here until tomorrow ends…
到明天結束為止 你就一直待在這裡苟延殘喘
in deep despair.
與絕望相伴吧
Mio…
澪…
It's hopeless.
結束了
If I can't loop, I can't redo anything.
不能進入輪迴，就再也無法重來了
I'm breaking that promise again. I'm not protecting anyone.
我又一次食言了，我誰都保護不了
I'm sorry, Mio. I'm sorry, Ushio.
對不起，澪，對不起，潮
Eek! Am I interrupting?
你們在忙嗎？
Totsumu…
凸村…
Ms. Nagumo!
南雲老師
That's my last shot!
最後一發
That was close! I almost let her kill you, Shinpei.
好險，慎平差點就被殺掉了
Totsumura, Ms. Nagumo…
凸村先生，南雲老師
Nothing can get in our way now.
這樣就再也沒有阻礙我們的人了
Thank you.
謝謝
What?
甚麼？
MERCURY (II) CHLORIDE
（毒藥，升汞）
I was able to… drink it.
多虧了你們，我才能喝下它
Shinpei.
慎平…
Listen to me.
你們兩個聽我說
If one of us dies or gets fatally hurt…
我們之中如果有人死了 或是受了致命傷
I will immediately loop back.
我就會馬上進入輪迴，重來一次
-What?
甚麼？
You will kill yourself? How?
你要自殺嗎？怎麼做？
I'll use this.
到時我會用這個
You… brought the mercury (II) chloride.
你…這是升汞？你帶出來了嗎？
How much of this is fatal?
這個毒藥的致死量是多少？
Even a drop would do the trick.
一滴就不行了
Then drinking the whole bottle will do it for sure.
那如果全都喝下去的話，肯定會死吧
Yeah, but you'll suffer.
嗯，但那樣會很痛苦的
POISON MERCURY (II) CHLORIDE
（毒藥，升汞）
Yes. Let's hope I never use it.
嗯，希望不會用到它
Is this poison? You know how to die.
毒藥嗎？看來你已經習慣了死亡
Don't tell me you've come here many times?
你該不會走到這一步好幾次了吧
I don't even have to come often to deal with you.
即使第一次也不覺得這算甚麼，混蛋
Wow, I didn't think you would have the guts.
是嗎？沒想到你有這等覺悟
Listen… I will redo this many, many times.
聽好了 不管再來幾遍，我都會選擇重來
In the end… I will defeat you.
直到最後把你們打倒
F-For sure.
我一定會…
Hey!
喂
There's nothing I can do now. I'm sorry, Heine.
我已經無計可施了，抱歉，波稻
Forget him.
別管那傢伙了
Look at her. She's been repairing the damage I inflicted on her.
你看，這傢伙從剛才開始 就一直把我的侵蝕推了回來
Shinpei is giving his life…
慎平在賭上性命努力的時候
so I can't just go down easily!
我怎麼能就這麼睡去？
She's actually eroding me now!
這傢伙反過來侵蝕我了
It can't be. Are you the egg?
難道你就是「蛋」嗎？
Kill her! Don't worry about me!
快殺了她，不用管我
She disappeared?
消失了？
That bastard… He took her.
該死的，她被帶走了
Ushioh!
潮
Shinpei!
慎平
You'll be okay. I won't let go!
沒事了，我再也不會放開你了
I'm sorry, Shinpei. It's all my fault. Everyone, even Mio…
對不起，慎平，都是因為我 大家才…澪也…
No!
不對
Don't look back. Just look at the present.
別回頭往後看了，只看現在
We will defeat them. Even if it costs me my life.
我會打倒那些傢伙的 就算耗盡我的生命也在所不惜
I'll go anywhere. As many times as you want me to.
無論多少次 無論去哪裡，我都會去的
I'll be with you, Shinpei.
只要和你一起
In other words, you are a time traveler.
也就是說，你是時光旅行者
Yes.
是的
Yes?
甚麼？
Yes. We just returned from the future.
是的，我們剛從未來回來
JULY 22 (FIFTH LOOP)
（7月22日　第五輪）